<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Read on Code One</title>
    <link>http://codeone.io/read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Read on Code One</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:11 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://codeone.io/read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Patient</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-11-be-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-11-be-patient/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/be-patient&#xA;Be Patient One thing I figured out later in life is generally (at least in the tech business in Silicon Valley), great people have great outcomes. You just have to be patient. Every person I met at the beginning of my career twenty years ago, where I looked at them and said, “Wow, that guy or gal is super capable—so smart and dedicated”…all of them, almost without exception became extremely successful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Lucky</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-10-how-to-get-lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-10-how-to-get-lucky/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/how-to-get-lucky&#xA;How to Get Lucky Why do you say, “Get rich without getting lucky”?&#xA;In 1,000 parallel universes, you want to be wealthy in 999 of them. You don’t want to be wealthy in the fifty of them where you got lucky, so we want to factor luck out of it.&#xA;But getting lucky would help, right?&#xA;Just recently, Babak Nivi, my co-founder, and I were talking on Twitter about how one gets lucky, and there are really four kinds of luck we were talking about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find Work That Feels Like Play</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-09-find-work-that-feels-like-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-09-find-work-that-feels-like-play/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/find-work-that-feels-like-play&#xA;Find Work That Feels Like Play Humans evolved as hunters and gatherers where we all worked for ourselves. It’s only at the beginning of agriculture we became more hierarchical. The Industrial Revolution and factories made us extremely hierarchical because one individual couldn’t necessarily own or build a factory, but now, thanks to the internet, we’re going back to an age where more and more people can work for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prioritize and Focus</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-08-prioritize-and-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:08 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-08-prioritize-and-focus/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/prioritize-and-focus&#xA;Prioritize and Focus I’ve encountered plenty of bad luck along the way. The first little fortune I made I instantly lost in the stock market. The second little fortune I made, or should have made, I basically got cheated out of by my business partners. It’s only the third time around that has been a charm.&#xA;Even then, it has been a slow and steady struggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Paid for Your Judgment</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-07-get-paid-for-your-judgment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:07 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-07-get-paid-for-your-judgment/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/get-paid-for-your-judgment&#xA;Get Paid for Your Judgment Choosing what kinds of jobs, careers, or fields you get into and what sort of deals you’re willing to take from your employer will give you much more free time. Then, you don’t have to worry as much about time management. I would love to be paid purely for my judgment, not for any work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find a Position of Leverage</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-06-find-a-position-of-leverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-06-find-a-position-of-leverage/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/find-a-position-of-leverage&#xA;Find a Position of Leverage We live in an age of infinite leverage, and the economic rewards for genuine intellectual curiosity have never been higher. [11] Following your genuine intellectual curiosity is a better foundation for a career than following whatever is making money right now. [11]&#xA;Knowledge only you know or only a small set of people knows is going to come out of your passions and your hobbies, oddly enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build or Buy Equity in a Business</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-05-build-or-buy-equity-in-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-05-build-or-buy-equity-in-a-business/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/build-or-buy-equity-in-a-business&#xA;Build or Buy Equity in a Business If you don’t own a piece of a business, you don’t have a path towards financial freedom.&#xA;Why is owning equity in a business important to becoming rich?&#xA;It’s ownership versus wage work. If you are paid for renting out your time, even lawyers and doctors, you can make some money, but you’re not going to make the money that gives you financial freedom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take on Accountability</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-04-take-on-accountability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-04-take-on-accountability/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/take-on-accountability&#xA;Take on Accountability Embrace accountability and take business risks under your own name. Society will reward you with responsibility, equity, and leverage.&#xA;To get rich, you need leverage. Leverage comes in labor, comes in capital, or it can come through code or media. But most of these, like labor and capital, people have to give to you. For labor, somebody has to follow you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play Long-Term Games with Long-Term People</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-03-play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-03-play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people&#xA;Play Long-Term Games with Long-Term People You said, “All the returns in life, whether in wealth, relationships, or knowledge, come from compound interest.” How does one know if they’re earning compound interest?&#xA;Compound interest is a very powerful concept. Compound interest applies to more than just compounding capital. Compounding capital is just the beginning.&#xA;Compounding in business relationships is very important.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find and Build Specific Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-02-find-and-build-specific-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-02-find-and-build-specific-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/find-and-build-specific-knowledge&#xA;Find and Build Specific Knowledge Sales skills are a form of specific knowledge.&#xA;There’s such a thing as “a natural” in sales. You run into them all the time in startups and venture capital. When you meet someone who is a natural at sales, you just know they’re amazing. They’re really good at what they do. That is a form of specific knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understand How Wealth Is Created</title>
      <link>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-01-understanding-how-wealth-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 01:01:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://codeone.io/read/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/1-1-01-understanding-how-wealth-is-created/</guid>
      <description>ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;A GUIDE TO WEALTH AND HAPPINESS&#xA;Original article: https://www.navalmanack.com/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/understanding-how-wealth-is-created&#xA;PART I - WEALTH How to get rich without getting lucky.&#xA;BUILDING WEALTH Making money is not a thing you do—it’s a skill you learn.&#xA;Understand How Wealth Is Created I like to think that if I lost all my money and you dropped me on a random street in any English-speaking country, within five or ten years I’d be wealthy again because it’s just a skillset I’ve developed that anyone can develop.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
